How did one woman save 2500 children?
The Courageous Heart of Irena Sendler is a drama, war
film directed by John Kent Harrison.
Irena Sendler is a Catholic social worker who has sympathized with the Jews since her childhood, when
her physician father died of typhus contracted while treating poor Jewish patients.
When she initially proposes saving Jewish children from the Warsaw Ghetto, her idea is met with
skepticism by fellow workers, her parish priest, and even her own mother Janina.
Irena Sendler, played by Anna Paquin.
Stefan Zgrzembski, played by Goran Višnjić.
Ewa Rozenfeld, played by Michelle Dockery.
Hannah Rozenfeld, played by Danuta Stenka.
Jadwiga, played by Maja Ostaszewska.
Dr. Janusz Korczak, played by Krzysztof Pieczyński.
The Courageous Heart of Irena Sendler is a 2009
television film directed by John Kent Harrison.
The teleplay by Harrison and Lawrence John Spagnola, based on the 2007 biography Die Mutter der Holocaust-Kinder: Irena Sendler und die geretteten Kinder aus dem
Warschauer Ghetto, focuses on Irena Sendler, a Polish social worker who smuggled approximately 2,500 Jewish children to safety during World War II.
The Hallmark Hall of Fame production was filmed on location in Riga, Latvia.
It was broadcast on CBS channels in North America on April 19, 2009, and
released to DVD in Hallmark Gold Crown stores in June of that year.
The film explores themes of nazi, holocaust (shoah), world
war ii, biography, based on true story.
The tone is emotional.